Guide to the Andrew Wellington Cordier Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series V:The United Nations Period And Related Files
  - Subseries V.2: Personal Correspondence and Administrative Files of Cordier
    - Sub-subseries V.2.4: Chronological Files 1950(?)-1962
      - Chronological file: Oct-Dec 1960 (Box 55)
      - Chronological file: Jan-Mar 1961 (Box 56)
      - Chronological file: Apr-Jun 1961 (Box 56)
      - Chronological file: Jul-Sep 1961 (Box 56)
      - Chronological file: Oct-Dec 1961 (Box 56)
      - Chronological file: Jan-Aug 1962 (Box 56)
    - Sub-subseries V.2.5: Miscellaneous Personal Files
      - Biographical Data: Correction of Birth Records, 1960 (Box 57)
      - Biographical data: Hartville-East Nimishillen Community, Ohio 1952 Biographical data: Miscellaneous materials (Box 57)
      - Biographical data: US Government International Organizations Loyalty (Box 57)
      - Board 1953-1954 (AWC form and questionnaire) (Box 57)
      - Biographical Data: Biographical Sketch file 1950-1961 (Box 57)
      - Biographical Data: "Who's Who" correspondence 1950-1961 (Box 57)
      - Biographical Data: Biographical materials; 1946-1948 (Box 57)
      - Press articles (clippings): 1950s-1960s (Box 57)
      - Press articles (clippings): 1956 (Box 57)
      - Press articles (clippings): 1957 (Box 57)
      - Press articles (clippings): 1958 (Box 57)
      - Press articles (clippings): 1959 (Box 57)
      - Press articles (clippings): 1960 (Box 57)
      - Press articles (clippings): 1961-1962 (Box 57)
      - Profiles, tributes: 1950s-1960s (Box 57)
      - Entertainment 1950-1962 (Mr. Cordier's personal entertaining as well as official (see also membership files) entertainment of Secretary-General & Under Secretaries) (Box 58)
      - Entertainment: 1950-1954 (Box 58)
      - Entertainment: 1960 (Box 58)
      - Entertainment: 1955 (Box 58)
      - Entertainment: 1961 (Box 58)
      - Entertainment: 1956 (Box 58)
      - Entertainment: 1962 (Box 58)
      - Entertainment: 1957 (Box 58)
      - Entertainment: "Congo" Club luncheon meeting SG's conference room, 38th floor 1961 (Box 58)
      - Entertainment: 1958 (Box 58)
      - Entertainment: 1959 (Box 58)
      - Memberships: American Clipper Club (Box 58)
      - Memberships: American Association for the United Nations, Great Neck Chapter, Advisory Committee (Box 58)
      - Memberships: American Association for the United Nations, Board of Directors 19 (Box 58)
      - Memberships: Century Association, New York 1954-1960 (used for luncheons and dinners) (Box 58)
      - Memberships: Council on Foreign Relations 1956-1959 (Box 58)
      - Memberships: Martha Kinney Cooper Ohioana Library Association 1961 Memberships: Rockefeller Center Luncheon Club 1950-1961 (used for luncheons) (Box 58)
      - Memberships: Transworld Airlines 1952-1953 (Box 58)
      - Memberships: University of Chicago Alumni 1957-1961 (Box 58)
      - Manchester College, North Manchester, Indiana: Correspondence 1949-l962, 1968 (Box 59)
      - Manchester College:
        - March of Progress Campaign 1961 (Box 59)
        - General Correspondence 1961 (Box 59)
        - Summary of contributions and pledges 1961 (Box 59)
        - Correspondence with W. J. Christie 1961 (Box 59)
        - Correspondence with Alumni 1961 (Box 59)
        - Luncheon for Manchester Alumni given by Mr. and Mrs. Cordier, 15 April 1961 at UN Headquarters (invitations, replies, table seating, etc.) (Box 59)
    - Sub-subseries V.2.6: Public Addresses & Papers, Honorary Degrees, Awards
      Period covered 1946 -1962)(Correspondence files). These files contain texts where available. However as many talks were given extemporaneously there is often no record on file. This does not mean that a transcript does not exist somewhere. (2) Unless otherwise specified the quotes in the following list indicate the topic of Mr. Cordier's talk. (3) In preparing this list 1 was not able to exhaustive research on each file so that there may be some gaps as to place, topic, etc. There may also be some errors as I did not proof read this list with anyone. Doreen Geary February
      - 1946 Radio appearances (1 Folder) (Box 60)
      - 1947 Radio appearances (1 Folder) (Box 60)
      - 1946-1947 Speaking engagements and invitations to speak (1 Folder) (Box 60)
      - 1948 Speaking engagements, and invitations to speak (1 Folder) (Box 60)
      - Individual Files: (Box 60)
      - 11 Aug 1948 United Nations Summer Course, Lake Success, N. Y. "General Assembly" (Text on file: Yes) (Box 60)
      - 24 Oct 1948 American Church in Paris, Paris France, Sunday morning worship."Toward World Peace Through United Nations" (Text on file: No) (Box 60)
      - 10 Jan 1949 New School tor Social Research, New York, N.Y. "General Assembly" (Text on file: No) (Box 61)
      - 28 Jan 1949 American Council on Education, Washington,DC "Education in World Affairs" (Text on file: No) (Box 61)
      - 31 Jan 1949 Juniata College, Huntingdon, Pennsylvania. Commencement address (Box 61)
      - 11 Feb 1949 United Nations Staff lecture series (UN Hq.) "General Assembly" (Text on file: Yes) (Box 61)
      - 14 Feb 1949 Elizabethtown College, Elizabethtown, Pennsylvania (Text on file: No) (Box 61)
      - 15 Feb 1949 Goshen College, Goshen, Indiana (lecture series). (Text on file: No) (Box 61)
      - 17 Feb 1949 Warsaw, Indiana. Joint Dinner meeting Rotary Club, Kiwanis, local teachers, et al. (Text on file: No) (Box 61)
      - 17 Feb 1949 Association for Supervision & Curriculum Development of the National Education Association. Conference on the United Nations, New York City. Address at Lake Success, NY. "Achievements of the United Nations" (Text on file: No) (Box 61)
      - 12 Mar 1949 American Association for the United Nations, Nil" 4th annual conference on the UN, Hotel Roosevelt, NYC. "Decisions of the Paris Assembly" (Text on file: No) (Box 61)
      - 16 Mar 1949 Commission on World Peace of the Methodist Church, UN Seminar, NYC 15-17 March 1949. Address at Lake Success. (Text on file: No) (Box 61)
      - 31 Mar 1949 US National Commission for UNESCO, Cleveland, Ohio. "Where Does the UN Stand Today!" (Text on file: No) (Box 61)
      - 16 May 1949 United Lutheran Church, UN Dinner, Holy Trinity Lutheran Church, New York, N.Y. (Text on file: No) (Box 61)
      - 28 May 1949 Women's Press Club of NY, Statler Hotel, NYC "Appraisal of the UN" (Text on file: No) (Box 61)
      - 18 Jun 1949 Conference. Church of Brethren, Ocean Grove. N.J. "Mobilizing Resources for Peace" (Text on file: No) (Box 61)
      - 28 Jun 1949 Hunter College High School. New York, N.Y. Commencement Address. (Text on file: No) (Box 61)
      - 8 Jul 1949 YMCA Executives, Eastern Region, Silver Bay, N.Y. (Lake George area) (Text on file: No) (Box 61)
      - 19 Jul 1949 New York University, NYC. Institute for Annual Review of United Nations Affairs. "General Assembly: Role and Function: Third. Session" (Text on file: Yes) (Box 61)
      - 28 Jul 1949 Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana (Text on file: Yes--excerpts) (Box 61)
      - 6 Aug 1949 Internationa1 Ladies" Garment Workers' Union, UN Institute, UN Hq. (Text on file: No) (Box 61)
      - 17 Sep 1949 NBC-TV, New York City. Interview by Leon except for a Pearson. "General Assembly" (Text on file: No—except for draft list of questions) (Box 61)
      - 4 Nov 1949 United Council of Church Women, World. Community Day. Interview recorded at UN Hq. "Structure & Functions of the UN and its Achievements" (Text on file: No) (Box 61)
      - 4 Nov 1949 UN Worldwide Club, Lake Success, NY. (Text on file: No) (Box 61)
      - 5 Nov 1949 Indianapolis Branch of the English Speaking Union, Indianapolis, Indiana. (Cordier, Romulo, et al). (Text on file: No) (Box 61)
      - 13 Nov 1949 US Chamber of Commerce, luncheon at Great Neck, N.Y. "General Assembly". (Text on file: No) (Box 61)
      - 26 Jan 1950 Scarborough Presbyterian Church, Scarborough, NY. (Men's group) "United Nations & Peace". (Text on file: No) (Box 61)
      - 4 Feb 1950 Purdue University, Lafayette, Indiana. (Text on file: No) (Box 61)
      - 5 Feb 1950 Elkhart Sunday Evening Club, Elkhart, Indiana NU (Text on file: No) (Box 61)
      - 6 Feb 1950 Dayton Council on World Affairs, Dayton, Ohio. "Progress of the United Nations". (Text on file: No) (Box 61)
      - 24 Feb 1950 Third United Nations Institute (sponsored by UN Public Information Dept., UNESCO and New York University, held at UN Hq. Lake Success, N.Y. Dinner meeting, Waldorf Astoria (While a speech Folder was made for this event it would appear that Mr. Cordier did not participate in the program but was a guest at the speakers' table at the dinner). (Text on file: No) (Box 61)
      - 17 Mar 1950 Laymen's Movement for a Christian World, Annual Yes Dinner.-"Moral Basis of the Work of the UN" (Statler Hotel, NYC). (Text on file: Yes) (Box 61)
      - 24 Mar 1950 First Methodist Church Men's Club, Evanston, Ill. "International Situation and the UN" (Text on file: No) (Box 61)
      - 24 Mar 1950 North Central Association of Colleges & Secondary Schools, Chicago, Ill. "U.N." (Box 61)
      - 20 May 1950 Haverford College, Pennsylvania (dinner honoring Clarence Pickett) "Quaker Role in the World Today" (Text on file: No) (Box 61)
      - 19 Jun 1950 Penn Association of Colleges and Univer­sities, Dickinson College, Carlisle Pa ''The UN and the World Crises" (Tape not good) (Box 61)
      - 22 Jun 1950 American Seminar (Sherwood Eddy group) Town, Hall, New York (Text on file: No) (Box 61)
      - 29 Ju1 1950 Elkhart Daily Truth, Elkhart, Indiana--article "The United Nations in Korea" (Text on file: Yes) (Box 61)
      - 26 Oct 1950 Northeastern Indiana Teachers' Assoc., Fort Wayne, Ind. ''The United Nations and World Peace" (Text on file: No) (Box 61)
      - 27 Oct 1950 North Central Indiana Teachers Assoc. South Bend, Ind. (Text on file: No) (Box 61)
      - 27 Oct 1950 Manchester College, North Manchester, Ind. (Text on file: No) (Box 61)
      - 30 Dec 1950 UN TV program "UN Stamp Club". Mr. Cordier spoke on UN activities (Text on file: No) (Box 61)
      - 8 Feb 1951 Alleghany College, Meadville, Pa. Sturtevant Lecture "Evolution of International Organizations" (Text on file: No) (Box 61)
      - 11 Feb 1951 National Education Association, Assoc. for Supervision & Curriculum Development, annual meeting "The Schools and World Affairs" (Detroit Michigan). (Text on file: Yes) (Box 61)
      - 1 Mar 1951 New York Young Republican Club luncheon talk Schwarz' Restaurant, New York City (Text on file: No) (Box 61)
      - 8 Mar 1951 Purdue University, Lafayette, Indiana (undergraduates dinner) (Text on file: No) (Box 61)
      - 2 Jul 1951 National Education Association, 89th annual meeting, San Francisco (Box 61)
      - 20 Jul 1951 Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana, Conference on Problems of American Foreign Policy (Text on file: No) (Box 61)
      - 23-24 Jul 1951 World Affairs Institute, Social Science Foundation, Univ. of Denver, Denver, 23 "UN Bulwark of Freedman" (Text on file: Yes) (Box 62)
      - 19 Sep 1951 Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, Round Table on World Affairs in Extension Education. "General Assembly" (Text on file: No) (Box 62)
      - 9 Oct 1951 Radio interview __ John MacVane (American Broadcasting) and UN Correspondents Assoc at Flushing Meadow "United --Or Not" (Text on file: Yes) (Box 62)
      - 29 Apr 1952 Office of Naval Research, Port Washington: Research Reserve" Seminar (UN hq.) (Text on file: No) (Box 62)
      - 29 Apr 1952 Radio interview --John MacVane (American Broadcasting Co.) and UN Correspondents Assoc as UN hq. New York. "United--or Not" (Text on file: Yes) (Box 62)
      - 2 Jun 1952 Otterbein College, Westerville, Ohio; commencement address & honorary degree (Text on file: No) (Box 62)
      - 22 Jun 1952 Church of the Brethren, annual conference, Richmond, Virginia "Striving for a Better World Through Troubled Times" (Text on file: Yes) Tape (2 reels) and transcript of 1 tape (Box 62)
      - 24 Jun 1952 Sherwood Eddy Seminar, UN hq (Text on file: No) (Box 62)
      - 1 July 1952 American Library Association (Public Documents Com.) and UN Library, mtg. UN Hq (Text on file: No) (Box 62)
      - 15 July 1952 Harvard University Summer School, International Seminar, Cambridge Mass.(Contents cataloged: Kissinger, Henry. (Text on file: No) (Box 62)
      - 25 July 1952 National University Extension Association, Debate Handbook, article by AWC (1948 & 1952) (Text on file: No) (Box 62)
      - 29 July 1952 National Council of Churches; Morning Chapel, NU tv show (Text on file: No) (Box 62)
      - 26 August 1952 Columbia University, School of Journalism (visit to the UN) (Text on file: No) (Box 62)
      - 3 Sep 1952 US Armed Forces Information School (UN Hq.) (Text on file: No) (Box 62)
      - 24 Sep 1952 Columbia University, WKCR Recorded inyerview by Peter Kenen (Text on file: No) (Box 62)
      - 5 Oct 1952 Astbury Church, Tuckahoe 7, N.Y. (Methodist) (Text on file: No) (Box 62)
      - 6 Oct 1952 Conference of International Non-Governmental Organizations, UN Hq. (Text on file: Yes) (Box 62)
      - 23 Oct 1952 US Army War College, UN Hq. (Text on file: No) (Box 62)
      - 26 Oct 1952 American Association for the UN, North Shore Branch, Nassau County, Manhasset High School (UN week) (Text on file: No) (Box 62)
      - 18 Nov 1952 The Touchdown Club of New York, luncheon. (Text on file: No) (Box 62)
      - 12 Dec 1952 US National War College, UN hq., luncheon) (Text on file: No) (Box 62)
      - 6 Jan 1953 Institute for Religion & Social Studies, Jewish Theological Seminary --(Moments of Discovery series) (autobiographical talk) (Text on file: Yes) (Box 62)
      - 27 Jan 1953 New York_.City Interschool Council for UNESCO at UN hq. "The United Nations" (Text on file: Yes) (Box 62)
      - 4 Feb 1953 Dayton Council onWorld Affairs, Dayton, Ohio "Strength Through the United Nations" (Text on file: No) (Box 62)
      - 5 & 6 Feb 1953 Manchester College, North Manchester, Indiana, 2 day program (text of remark in answer to a question on the McCarran investigation) (Text on file: Yes) (Box 62)
      - 9 February 1953 Penn State Christian Association (Penn State College, State College, Pa.) "United Nations" (Text on file: No) (Box 62)
      - 12 Feb 1953 New York University, Institute on UN Affairs (Text on file: No) (Box 62)
      - 13 Feb 1953 US Chamber of Commerce group (UN Hq.) (Text on file: No) (Box 62)
      - 2 Mar 1953 American Association for the United Nations, Washington, D.C. (Conon US Responsibility for World Leadership). (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 5 Mar 1953 YMCA of the City of New York, at UN Hq. (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 11 Mar 1953 Opening ceremony UN Postage Stamp Exhibition Excerpt only (see UN radio program) (Box 63)
      - 3 Apr 1953 City of New York, reception for Metropolitan N.Y. Combat Contingent, returning from Korea (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 17 Apr 1953 New York University, Cost of Peace Series: AWC topic "Cost of Peace" (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 7 Jun 1953 Albright College, Reading, Pa. Commencement address and honorary degree. "Youth's contri­bution to an Age of Tension" (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 17 Jun 1953 Rotary Club, Brooklyn, N.Y. (visit to UN) (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 13 Jul 1953 Purdue University, Lafayette, Indiana. Uniersity Convocation. "The UN and Korea" (Text on file: Yes, extract of address) (Box 63)
      - 2 Aug 1953 International House, New York City. Guestspeaker, Sunday Supper (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 8 Sep 1953 United Nations, General Staff Meeting. Theme "The UN and the General Assembly" (Text on file: Yes (Box 63)
      - 15 Sep 1953 New Yolk Uni., 5th Inst. for Annual Review of United Nations Affairs. "General Assembly" (Text on file: Yes + text of discussion) (Box 63)
      - 15 Oct 1953 US Army War College, UN Hq. "Office of the Secretary-General" (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 16 Oct 1953 Inter-Parliamentary Union' (UN Hq). "UN Secretariat and Work of t he General Assembly" (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 20 Oct 1953 US Chamber of Commerce, Panel Discussion, UN Hq. Theme: "The United Nations" (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 13 Nov 1953 YMCA Executives, Metropolitan Area, New York, at UN Hq. (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 17 Nov 1953 Methodist Board of World Peace, at UN Hq. (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 17 Nov 1953 Phi Beta Kappa Associates, Colony Club, New York. "Outlook for World Peace through the United Nations" (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 8 Dec 1953 Indiana Council of Churches, UN Seminar, N.Y. (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 11 Dec 1953 Penn State Christian Assoc., Penn State College, State College, Pa. Visit to UN (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 18 Dec 1953 University of the State of New York, Board of Regents, visit to the UN (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 29 Dec 1953 Executive Club of Chicago, Chicago (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 11 Jan 1954 Church 9f the Brethren, volunteer service group visit to UN (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 7 Late Jan/Early February Recorded interview with Henry Cassidy of NBC, done at UN hq. Subject: forthcoming conon Indo-China, Geneva April 1954. (Text on file: No--Try U.N. Radio) (Box 63)
      - 5 Feb 1954 Church of the Brethren, Youth Seminar, UN Hq (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 15 Feb 1954 National Council of Churches, United Church Women, Christian World Relationships Committee, Carnegie Endowment building, New York "Current Major Questions Confronting the UN" (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 22 Feb 1954 State Teachers College, Indiana, Pennsylvania "The American Stake in the United Nations" (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 5 Mar 1954 World Day of Prayer broadcast (CBS Religious Broadcasts) (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 11 Mar 1954 Canadian Business & Professional Women, UN Hq (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 22 Apr 1954 City of New York reception for 45th Infantry returning from Korea (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 23 Apr 1954 Association of International Relations Clubs, Yes (partially. 7th annual conference, Hunter College, N.Y. edited text) "International Relations Clubs and the UN" (Text on file: Yes, partially edited text) (Box 63)
      - 27 Apr 1954 Council of Bishops of the Methodist Church, UN Hq.. "General Assembly" (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 24 Apr 1954 The Associated Church Press (UN Hq.) (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 30 May 1954 Cedar Crest College, Allentown, Pennsylvania, commencement address. (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 27 Jun 1954 National Council of Churches "Frontiers Of Faith"(the NBC-VT Panel discussion. "What should be role of the churches in international affairs'?" (Text on file: No, only the questions put to Mr. Cordier) (Box 63)
      - 28 Jun 1954 National Conference of Christians and Jews, Inter­cultural travel seminar group, UN Hq. (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 1 Jul 1954 National Education Association Convention meeting, UN Hq. Theme "The Citizen and the UN", Mr. Cordier chairman of the session. (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 7 Aug 1954 The Pennsylvania State University, State College, Pennsylvania, Summer session commencement address (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 21 Aug 1954 United Nations Association of Greater Chicago (Dag Hammarskdjold and Mr. Cordier) (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 15 Sep 1954 New York University, Sixth Institute, Annual Review of UN Affairs "General Assembly" (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 21 Oct 1954 New York University, Graduate School of Arts & Science. "Position of the US in the Ninth Session, General Assenbly" (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 8 Nov 1954 World Affairs 'Council of Northern California. "Experts Off the Record" program (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 19 Nov 1954 Association of Coverning Boards, UN Hq (Text on file: Yes) (Box 63)
      - 6 Dec 1954 Indiana Council of Churches, UN Hq. (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 4 Feb 1955 Church of the Brethren, Adult Seminar, UN Hq. (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 21 Feb 1955 Dartmouth College, Hanover, N.H .' Great Issues Course. "UN--evaluation of a Decade" (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 27 Feb 1955 American Association for the United Nations, annual conference, Washington, D.C. Remarks, opening session. (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 7 Mar 1955 American Association for the United Nations, Great Neck Chapter. "Behind the Scenes at the UN" (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 12 Mar 1955 Manchester College, Special Convocation." Manchester College and Leadership in Public Life." (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 18 Mar 1955 American Society for Public Administration, panel session on Administrative Problems in the UN. Chaired by Mr. Cordier. (Hotel New Yorker, New York, N.Y.) (Text on file: Yes, resume of panel discussion) (Box 63)
      - 24 Mar 1955 Wellesley College, Wellesley, Mass., students Forum (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 1 Apr 1955 World Federation of United Nations Associations, Week-end study course, UN Hq. "The UN Today" (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 23 Apr 1955 Prairie Club of Des Moines, Des Moines, Iowa. "United Nations: Evaluation of a Decade" (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 24 Apr 1955 Plymouth Congregational Church, Des Moines, Iowa Sunday morning sermon. (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 24 Apr 1955 Iowa Association for the United Nations; Des Moines Iowa. Coffee hour. (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 2 May 1955 National Association of State Universities, 60th annual mtg., University Club, New. York City "United Nations: Evaluation of a Decade" (Text on file: Yes) (Box 63)
      - 15 May 1955 New York Times Youth Forum, Dumont Telecenter, New York City. Topic: "Diplomatic Negotiations--how much should the public know? (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 16 Jul 1955 Silver Bay Conference of the Christian World Mission, National Council of Churches, Silver Bay, NY (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 2 Aug 1955 Daily News WPIX Three Star News Program, New Yolk NY (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 27 Aug 1955 Kent State University, Kent, Ohio. Honorary degree, and commencement address. "Role of Education in Promoting Peace and Understanding" (Text on file: Yes) (Box 63)
      - 28 Aug 1955 Church of the Brethren, Hartville, Ohio. Sunday morning worship (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 3 Sep 1955 Fifth Annual Institute for Methodist Men, Depauw University, Greencastle, Indiana (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 13 Sep 1955 National Council of Women's Organizations of the Presbyterian Church, UN Hq. (Presentation by than of gift of Ecuadorian rugs to the UN (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 17 Sep 1955 American Broadcasting Co. "Assignment 10" Recorded interview. UN Hq. (Text on file: No) (Box 63)
      - 11 Oct 1955 Council for Social Action, Congregational Christian Church, NY UN Seminar. George Washington Hotel dinner meeting (Text on file: No) (Box 64)
      - 18 Oct 1955 Riverside Church Men's Class. "Latest Developments in the United Nations." New York, N.Y. (Text on file: No) (Box 64)
      - 23 Oct 1955 Great Neck Committee for UN Day -10th anniversary UN (Great Neck, N.Y.) (Text on file: No) (Box 64)
      - 24 Oct 1955 National Broadcasting Co.,NY Recorded message for opening of UN week (Suggested draft message) (Box 64)
      - 24 October 1955 New York University, convocation for foreign students & scholars, N.Y.U, New York. "The University Student and the UN" (Text on file: No) (Box 64)
      - 10 November 1955 Council on Student Travel, Carnegie Bldg., New York. Sixth annual con"Role of International Travel in Resolving World Tension" (Text on file: No) (Box 64)